[
  {
    "id": "1618",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Who was Nephi’s nephew that wrote the third book in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": ["Enos"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1619",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "It came to pass that Enos knew that his father was a_____ man.",
    "answer": ["Just"],
    "options": ["Just", "Holy", "Unworthy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1620",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Was a prophet of the Lord and also the father of Enos?",
    "answer": ["Jacob"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1621",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1,27",
    "question": "How many chapters are in the book of Enos?",
    "answer": ["One", "1"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1622",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Enos was not taught in the language of his father, therefore he made up his own.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1623",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Who taught Enos of the nurture and admonition of the Lord?",
    "answer": ["Father"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1624",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:2",
    "question": "And I will tell you of the_____ which I had before God, before I received a remission of my sins.",
    "answer": ["Wrestle"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1625",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:2",
    "question": "The word wrestle is only mentioned once in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1626",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:3",
    "question": "Enos went to hunt_____ in the forest.",
    "answer": ["Beasts"],
    "options": ["Wild Game", "Bears", "Beasts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1627",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:3",
    "question": "Enos’s father spoke to him concerning eternal_____, and the joy of the saints, and those words sank deep into his heart.",
    "answer": ["Life"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1628",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:4",
    "question": "And my soul hungered; and I kneeled down before my_____.",
    "answer": ["Maker"],
    "options": ["Alter", "Maker", "Pile Of Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1629",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:4",
    "question": "Enos cried unto his Maker in mighty prayer and supplication for his own soul.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1630",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:4",
    "question": "Enos cried unto his Maker all day long, and when the night came, he raised his voice high that it reached the_____.",
    "answer": ["Heavens"],
    "options": ["Heavens", "Moon", "Stars"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1631",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:5",
    "question": "Who said: “Enos, thy sins are forgiven thee, and thou shalt be blessed”",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1632",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:6",
    "question": "And I, _____, knew that God could not lie; wherefore, my guilt was swept away.",
    "answer": ["Enos"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1633",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:7",
    "question": "Enos asked the Lord how it was done that his sins were forgiven.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1634",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:8",
    "question": "How was Enos’ guilt for his sins forgiven?",
    "answer": ["faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1635",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:8",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that two years would pass away before Christ would manifest himself in the flesh.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1636",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:8",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that his faith alone did not make him whole.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1637",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:9",
    "question": "When Enos heard the words of the Lord he began to feel a desire, for the welfare of his brethren, the_____.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1638",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:9",
    "question": "Enos poured out his whole soul unto God, for the welfare of the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1639",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "Enos struggled in the spirit while he was praying for the welfare of the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1640",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that he would visit his brethren according to their_____ in keeping his commandment.",
    "answer": ["Diligence"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1641",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "Enos was told by the Holy Ghost that the land of promise was a holy land.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1642",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that he would curse the land of promise save it be for the cause of_____.",
    "answer": ["Iniquity"],
    "options": ["Iniquity", "Wars", "Contentions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1643",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "Their transgressions will I bring down with sorrow upon their own_____.",
    "answer": ["Heads"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1644",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:11",
    "question": "After Enos heard the words of the Lord, his faith began to be unshaken in the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1645",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:11",
    "question": "Enos prayed unto the Lord with many long struggles, for his brethren, the_____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1646",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:12",
    "question": "Enos prayed and labored with all his diligence unto the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1647",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:12",
    "question": "The Lord said unto Enos that he would grant his desires because of his_____.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["Wishes", "Faith", "Humble Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1648",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:13",
    "question": "Enos desired of the Lord: That if the Nephites should fall because of transgression and the Lamanites should not be destroyed, that he would preserve the record of his people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1649",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:13",
    "question": "Enos desired that the record of his people be brought forth at some future day unto the_____; that they may be brought forth unto salvation.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1650",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:14",
    "question": "For at the present our struggles were vain in restoring Lamanites to the true_____.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1651",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites swore in their wrath that if it were possible, they would destroy the Nephites and their records, and also all the_____ of their fathers.",
    "answer": ["Customs"],
    "options": ["Traditions", "Customs", "Their Sign Language."]
  },
  {
    "id": "1652",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:15",
    "question": "Enos cried unto the Lord continually because he knew that he would preserve their records.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1653",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:15",
    "question": "The Lord said to Enos:  “Whatsoever thing ye shall ask in_____, believing that ye shall receive in the name of Christ, ye shall receive it”.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1654",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:15",
    "question": "Because Enos had faith in the Lord; he knew that whatsoever he asked of him, he would receive it.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1655",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:16",
    "question": "The Lord_____ with Enos that he would bring forth his records unto the Lamanites in his own due time.",
    "answer": ["Covenanted"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1656",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:16",
    "question": "Enos said that the Lord would bring forth his records unto the Lamanites when he would still be alive.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1657",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:17",
    "question": "Enos knew that the Lord would do with the records that which he had covenanted with him; wherefore his soul did_____.",
    "answer": ["Rest"],
    "options": ["Rest", "Yearn", "Wander"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1658",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:18",
    "question": "The Lord compared Enos’ faith like that of his_____.",
    "answer": ["Fathers"],
    "options": ["Brothers", "Fathers", "Children"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1659",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:19",
    "question": "Enos went about among the people of Nephi, _____ of things to come.",
    "answer": ["Prophesying"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1660",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:19",
    "question": "Enos testified to the Nephites of the things which he had heard and seen.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1661",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "And I Enos, _____ record that the people of Nephi did seek diligently to restore the Lamanites unto the true faith of God.",
    "answer": ["Bear"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1662",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "Enos and his brothers’ labors were in vain because the Lamanites hatred was fixed, and they were led by their evil nature.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1663",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "Because of their evil nature, the Lamanites became a wild, ferocious, and____ people.",
    "answer": ["Bloodthirsty"],
    "options": ["Mean", "Dirty", "Bloodthirsty"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1664",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "According to Enos, the Lamanites were full of idolatry and filth1ness; feeding upon beast’s of_____, and dwelling in tents.",
    "answer": ["Prey"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1665",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "The Lamanites would wander in the wilderness with a short skin girdle about their loins and their_____ shaven.",
    "answer": ["Heads"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1666",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "The Lamanites skill was not in the bow, and in the cimeter, and the ax.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1667",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Enos1:20",
    "question": "Many of the Lamanites did eat nothing but_____ meat; continually seeking to destroy the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["Raw"],
    "options": ["Raw", "Unhealthy", "Good"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1668",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "In his book Enos, he describes the way of life in the Nephite culture and also of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1669",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "The people of Nephi did not till the ground but raised cattle instead.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1670",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "The Nephites did till the land, and raised all kinds of grain, and fruit, and flocks of herds.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1671",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "The Nephites raised_____ of all manner of cattle of every kind, and goats, and wild goats.",
    "answer": ["Flocks"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1672",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:21",
    "question": "During the time that Enos was on the earth the Nephites did not have horses.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1673",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:22",
    "question": "Enos said that there were many prophets in the land among them but that the people were a_____ people, hard to understand.",
    "answer": ["Stiffnecked"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1674",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "Enos said that there was exceeding harshness, preaching and prophesying of_____, and contentions and destructions.",
    "answer": ["Wars"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1675",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding harshness, preaching and prophesying of wars, the people were continually reminded of death.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1676",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "The people were continually reminded of the judgments and _____ of God.",
    "answer": ["Power"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1677",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:23",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding great plainness of speech, it would keep the people from going down speedily to destruction.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1678",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:24",
    "question": "Enos did not see many wars between the Nephites and Lamanites in the course of his days.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1679",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:25",
    "question": "Enos was wrought upon the power of God that he must preach and prophesy unto the people and declare the word according to the truth which is in_____.",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1680",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:26",
    "question": "Enos declared in all his days to the truth which is in Christ, and rejoiced in it above that of the world.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1681",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Enos1:27",
    "question": "Enos said that he knew that he would go to the place of his rest, which is with his Redeemer; and knew that in him he would rest.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1682",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:27",
    "question": "Enos rejoiced in the day that his mortal shall put on_____; and shall stand before him; and would see his face with pleasure.",
    "answer": ["Immortality"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1683",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:27",
    "question": "Enos said that the Lord would say to him:  “Come unto me, ye blessed, there is a place prepared for you in the_____, of my Father”.",
    "answer": ["Mansions"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  }
]
